<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The simdjson library</title>
    <link>https://simdjson.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The simdjson library</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://simdjson.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simdjson.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simdjson.org/about/</guid>
      <description>The simdjson library uses three-quarters less instructions than state-of-the-art parser RapidJSON and fifty percent less than sajson. To our knowledge, simdjson is the first fully-validating JSON parser to run at gigabytes per second on commodity processors. It can parse millions of JSON documents per second on a single core. It takes advantage of modern microarchitectures, parallelizing with SIMD vector instructions, reducing branch misprediction, and reducing data dependency to take advantage of each CPU&amp;rsquo;s multiple execution cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simdjson.org/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simdjson.org/publications/</guid>
      <description> Academic Publications  Geoff Langdale, Daniel Lemire, Parsing Gigabytes of JSON per Second, VLDB Journal 28 (6), 2019.  Online articles  Daniel Lemire, Making Your Code Faster by Taming Branches, InfoQ, March 2020.  Blog posts  Geoff Langdale, Paper: Parsing Gigabytes of JSON per Second, February 2019.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://simdjson.org/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simdjson.org/software/</guid>
      <description>The library is part of major linux distributions like Ubuntu and Debian. It is in Microsoft vpkg. We publish it as single-header library as well as a CMake build from theGitHub repository. We have a simdjson organization on GitHub.
Quick Start Prerequisites: g++ (version 7 or better) or clang++(version 6 or better), and a 64-bit system (e.g., linux, Windows, FreeBSD, macOS).
 Pull simdjson.h and simdjson.cpp from our singleheader directory into a directory of your choice, along with the sample file twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://simdjson.org/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simdjson.org/talks/</guid>
      <description>Best Voted talk at QCon San Francisco 2019:

Performance Summit III (2020):</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>