<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The simdjson library</title>
    <link>https://simdjson.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The simdjson library</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://simdjson.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simdjson.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simdjson.org/about/</guid>
      <description>To our knowledge, simdjson is the first fully-validating JSON parser to run at gigabytes per second on commodity processors. It can parse millions of JSON documents per second on a single core. It takes advantage of modern microarchitectures, parallelizing with SIMD vector instructions, reducing branch misprediction, and reducing data dependency to take advantage of each CPU&amp;rsquo;s multiple execution cores. We support ARM NEON, SSSE3, AVX2, AVX-512 and POWER instructions, among others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://simdjson.org/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simdjson.org/publications/</guid>
      <description>Academic Publications John Keiser, Daniel Lemire, On-Demand JSON: A Better Way to Parse Documents?, Software: Practice and Experience (to appear) Geoff Langdale, Daniel Lemire, Parsing Gigabytes of JSON per Second, VLDB Journal 28 (6), 2019. John Keiser, Daniel Lemire, Validating UTF-8 In Less Than One Instruction Per Byte, Software: Practice &amp;amp; Experience 51 (5), 2021. Daniel Lemire, Number Parsing at a Gigabyte per Second, Software: Practice and Experience 51 (8), 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://simdjson.org/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simdjson.org/software/</guid>
      <description>The library is part of major linux distributions like Ubuntu and Debian and as a FreeBSD package. It is in Microsoft vcpkg. It is available as an MSYS2 package, from brew and from conan. We publish it as single-header library as well as a CMake build from theGitHub repository. We have a simdjson organization on GitHub.
Quick Start Prerequisites: g++ (version 7 or better) or clang++(version 6 or better), and a 64-bit system (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://simdjson.org/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simdjson.org/talks/</guid>
      <description>Best Voted talk at QCon San Francisco 2019 Performance Summit III (2020) </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
